<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Course Introduction &amp; Tools on Code in One Day: HTML &amp; CSS Crash Course</title>
    <link>/00-course-intro-and-tools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Course Introduction &amp; Tools on Code in One Day: HTML &amp; CSS Crash Course</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 19:57:51 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/00-course-intro-and-tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Class Introductions</title>
      <link>/00-course-intro-and-tools/class-introductions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/00-course-intro-and-tools/class-introductions/</guid>
      <description> QUESTIONS  Name
 What do you do?
 Why are you taking this class?
 Fun fact?
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Objectives</title>
      <link>/00-course-intro-and-tools/course-objectives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/00-course-intro-and-tools/course-objectives/</guid>
      <description> Gain an overview of how the internet works, the web development landscape, and the place of HTML and CSS in the web ecosystem
 Use HTML and CSS to mark up common types of web pages
 Build and deploy a basic website from scratch
 Describe the various opportunities to continue learning web development
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is front-end Development?</title>
      <link>/00-course-intro-and-tools/what-is-frontend-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 19:57:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/00-course-intro-and-tools/what-is-frontend-development/</guid>
      <description>Overview  Front-end web development, also known as client-side development is the practice of producing HTML, CSS and JavaScript for a website or Web Application so that a user can see and interact with them directly.  What are the primary technologies associated with front-end development?  HTML
 CSS
 Javascript
  How is front-end development differ from back-end development?  Backend development, is also known as server-side development and involves storing data on behalf of users or customers</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Tools</title>
      <link>/00-course-intro-and-tools/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 10:03:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/00-course-intro-and-tools/tools/</guid>
      <description>Text Editor:
 Why?: Text editor is a program that developers use to create and edit a range of programming language files. We&amp;rsquo;ll be using Atom, because it&amp;rsquo;s open source (free) and really good.
 Download Atom
    Browser:
 Why?: Google chrome is a robust browser with a variety of tools that are helpful to developers.
 Install Google Chrome
    Github:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keys to Success</title>
      <link>/00-course-intro-and-tools/keys-to-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 17:11:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/00-course-intro-and-tools/keys-to-success/</guid>
      <description>Practice, Practice, Practice: More you practice the concepts learned in class, the faster you&amp;rsquo;ll pick them up
 Don&amp;rsquo;t try to memorize anything: You&amp;rsquo;ll memorize things naturally through the act of doing things over and over again. Besides, if you don&amp;rsquo;t remember something just look it up (i.e. google).
 Work smarter not harder: In additional to looking things up, developers are really good at referencing past code that they&amp;rsquo;ve used in the past to solve problems they encounter in the present.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>